Luis Tena

Valencia, Venezuela



des.luistena@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/luistena



https://luistena.is-a.dev

Summary

With +9 years of experience, I have become a proficient Full-Stack Developer in JavaScript / TypeScript (Back End heavy) with enough knowledge in Python and DevOps. I am a creative person with a friendly and openminded co-worker attitude.

I have been an entrepreneur, an employee and I will always be a student ready for the next challenge.

You could also check my Github https://github.com/devluist

Experience



🐧 Full-Stack Developer

EmQu Technologies

Sep 2022 - Dic 2022 (4 months)

- FastAPI / Python development
- Nomad + Consul DevOps tasks

Full Stack Engineer

SIM Venezuela

Jun 2018 - Aug 2021 (3 years 3 months)

- DevOps:
- * Site Reliability Engineering. Sentry, Prometheus and Grafana SQL/PromQL gueries for reports, health checks, and monitoring
- * Automation Scripting development with Bash/Python
- * Servers setup: Nginx, domains, non-sudo users, custom ports, set ssh keys, firewall setup, etc
- React.js
- * Co-developer on some of the React projects for clients and internal project at the company

🔀 Full Stack Engineer

Universidad de Oriente (VE)

Sep 2017 - Mar 2018 (7 months)

Web app for data collection to increase tourism. This was a college project, made with Node is / Express.js and MongoDB.

I was in charge of the Backend, Architecture, and Admin Dashboard. I implemented Factory and Strategy Design patterns on the API.

There is demo based in a Venezuelan state here https://youtu.be/cBGeJUG1bu8

Entrepreneur

Self Employed

Dec 2013 - Mar 2015 (1 year 4 months)

This app was a Venezuelan freelance marketplace web app. You could see a demo at https://youtu.be/EGY NsZGuSc

- Back End with Python2.5 / Django 1.8
- Front End with CSS3 + Boostrap3 and HTML5
- Deployment to a Server through Openshift services

Education

🔀 Universidad de Oriente (VE)

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science 2008 - 2018

Licenses & Certifications

(A) Relational Databases - freeCodeCamp

https://www.freecodecamp.org/certification/dev_luist/relational-database-v8

Python Basic - HackerRank

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/a3392ff8dae8

Javascript Basic - HackerRank

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/08c571b46347

EF SET English Certificate 67/100 (C1 Advanced) - EF Standard English Test (EF SET)

https://www.efset.org/cert/HB4mJK

(A) Intermediate Python - freeCodeCamp

freecodecamp.org/certification/dev_luist/scientific-computing-with-python-v7

Back End Development and APIs - freeCodeCamp

freecodecamp.org/certification/dev luist/back-end-development-and-apis

Skills

TypeScript • JavaScript • Python • DevOps • GraphQL • NoSQL • Docker • Testing • Emotional Intelligence • Interpersonal Skills